next.ie 2017-06-02

# Next Ireland

## What are cookies?

Cookies are small text files that are stored on your PC, phone or other web enabled device when you visit the Next website. They are not harmful and do not contain any confidential information such as your home address, date of birth or credit card details. Cookies are an essential part of how our site works. Some of these cookies are required by our site to enable you to transact whilst other cookies enable us to give you an enhanced, personalised web experience.By using our site, you also consent to the use of these cookies.  

## Cookies are used on our site for the following reasons:

  1. To allow you to securely sign in to your Next Directory Account, so that you can use "My Account" features such as order information, making payments and viewing statements.
  2. To store the content of your online shopping bag whilst you browse the site and to complete an order.
  3. To record the areas of the website that you have visited, products you have viewed and time spent browsing, as well as the products you purchased. Next uses this information to help make the website more user friendly, develop our site design and to continuously improve the quality of the service we provide.
  4. To distribute visitors to our site evenly across platforms to ensure the content is served at the fastest possible speed.

We also offer you the facility to share your experience on our site through social sites such as facebook and twitter. By using these features, you are also consenting to allow cookies from these providers. More information about how these providers use cookies can be found at their websites. 

## Are Cookies Safe?

Yes. The information stored in cookies is safe and anonymous. They do not contain any information which could personally identify you and your account security is never compromised. You can find more information about cookies at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). For a video about cookies visit [www.google.co.uk/goodtoknow/data-on-the-web/cookies](http://www.google.co.uk/goodtoknow/data-on-the-web/cookies)

## Can I turn off cookies?

Next uses cookies to ensure that we provide the best possible standard of service to our online customers. However, as part of our privacy and security policy, we require your consent to use them. To withdraw your consent, or if you want to be notified each time a cookie is about to be used, you should amend the settings provided in your web browser to prevent us from storing cookies on your computer's hard drive. For information on how to disable cookies, please consult the "Help" tab of your browser via the menu bar.It must be noted that if you choose not to consent to the use of cookies, your experience of our site will be severely impaired and many integral aspects of the site, including (but not limited to) adding items to your shopping bag and accessing your account, will not work at all. 

## Our use of advertisement tracking

We also allow selected third parties who participate with us in marketing programmes to place cookies when you visit our site. These cookies enable us to monitor which adverts you see and click on to get to our site. We currently use two companies for this and you can see their privacy policies at the following addresses:

  1. Mediaplex: [www.mediaplex.com/mojo-privacy-statement](http://www.mediaplex.com/mojo-privacy-statement)
  2. DoubleClick: [www.google.com/policies/privacy/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)

These cookies are as safe as the ones used whilst you browse our site and neither of these third parties collects any personal data from which they would be able to identify individual customers.Next is not responsible for the content or privacy policies of third parties or other websites. 

## Security

Next Directory takes online security very seriously and use registered secure site under Verisign Certificate Authority.  
_How Do We Protect Your Information?_

We use a server certificate (also known as a digital certificate) to assure you of our identity and secure sockets layer (SSL) to encrypt data transmissions.

If you want to check our certificate/security you can do so using one of the following methods:

From your browser when you are within the Site:  
Microsoft Internet Explorer 4 or later  
Click on the gold padlock at the bottom right of your browser to bring up the details of this Site's Digital ID.

Mozilla Firefox  
Click on the yellow padlock at the bottom left of your browser to bring up the security information.

Opera  
Click on the padlock within the address bar of your browser to bring up the security information.

At the Verisign web site  
The VeriSign web site enables you to validate the security of our pages online. Validate our secure server. Alternatively, click on the VeriSign Secured® Seal throughout secure areas of nextdirect.com.

The security measures described above are just some of the administrative, technical, and physical steps we take to protect your personal information. However, the open nature of the Internet means that an absolute guarantee of security cannot be offered, and you should be aware that even with all the measures we take, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information.

## Privacy

Next are committed to complying with the Data Protection Act 1998 and have published this guide to help you understand how and why Next collect information from you, to whom such information is disclosed and what your rights are. You can access our Website home page and browse our site without disclosing your personal data. However, when you register with Next you will be asked to provide certain information about yourself. 

_What Information Do We Collect And How Do We Obtain It?_

We receive information in one of two ways either directly from you when you register with us or from a third party such as credit reference agencies (for example to assess your credit rating).

If you register with us you will be asked to provide certain information such as your name, address, details of your credit card (only if you are paying by credit card), telephone number and email address so that we can process and fulfil your order, notify you of your order status and inform you of special offers and promotions.

_How Do We Use Your Information?_

We use the information that we collect about you to: 

  1. Process your orders
  2. Manage your account - see also "Use of credit reference agency information".
  3. Administer this website.
  4. Monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage to help us develop and improve the design and layout of the site.
  5. Notify you about enhancement to our services, such as changes to the website, new services and special offers that may be of interest.

You agree that we may use personal information in order to conduct appropriate anti fraud checks. Personal information that you provide may be disclosed to a credit reference or fraud prevention agency, who may keep a record of that information. If you have given us permission to send you information about our products and services by telephone, email or in writing, Next will do so in accordance with the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations 2003 and the Direct Marketing Association (DMA) Code of Practice. 

_Use of Credit Reference Agency Information and sharing of credit information._   
In the interests of responsible lending and for security purposes we may carry out searches with credit reference agencies when you register with Next and further searches may be carried out before deciding whether to accept orders and/or grant further credit. The agencies record these searches. We may also share information about you and the conduct of your account with credit reference agencies, other lenders and relevant third parties Information about you and other members of your household and those with whom you are financially linked maybe used to verify your identity and for the credit assessment of you and them. We may also use your information for payment recovery or fraud and debt tracing. We will pass on details of defaulting accounts to debt collection agencies. For details of the Credit Reference Agencies that we receive information from and share information with write to the Group Data Protection Manager at Head Office or via dataprotection@nextdirect.com, quoting Security and Privacy Enquiry. 

_Who Does Next Disclose The Information It Collects To?_   
We use information about you for purposes other than the provision of a website shopping facility. As a result we may disclose your information to: 

  1. Credit Reference Agencies - for more information see above.
  2. Legal and debt recovery representatives for debt collection and debtor tracing purposes.
  3. Reputable companies to fulfil your order or process your data on our behalf.

We may combine your information with information we collect from other companies and use it to improve and personalize our services, content and advertising.  
This may also be done on a reciprocal basis. From time to time, we make portions of our customer list available to carefully screened companies. If you do not want your name and mailing details made available, or no longer choose to receive a Next catalog or wish to alert us to duplicate mailings, please call us on our helpline number or email marketing@next.com. Next is committed to respecting your privacy. 

## Keeping in Touch with You

We want to keep you up to date with information about new ranges, special offers and improvements to this site.

If you decide you do not want us to contact you, you can request that we stop using your information and that we stop mailing information to you by writing to the Group Data Protection Manager at Head Office or via dataprotection@nextdirect.com, quoting Security and Privacy Enquiry.

You may continue to receive mailings which are already on route to you for a short period of time while your request is being dealt with. 

## Your Rights Under the Data Protection Act 1998

You have a right to access the personal data that we hold on you. If you would like to see a copy please send a £10 fee and a written request to the Group Data Protection Manager at Head Office, quoting Security and Privacy Enquiry. If you think the information we hold on you is incorrect please contact the Group Data Protection Manager at Head Office or via dataprotection@nextdirect.com, quoting Security and Privacy Enquiry. 

## The Direct Marketing Association

Next is a member of the Direct Marketing Association (DMA) and is required to operate within the rules of the DMA's Code of Practice. This means that Next operate to a high level of commercial standards which are designed to : 

  1. Protect your privacy.
  2. Ensure that payments are secure.
  3. Let you know what you have agreed to.
  4. Sort out any complaints.

For more information on the DMA, visit www.dma.org.uk 

Next is also a member of the Mail Order Traders Association (MOTA) and subscribes to their Code of Practice. We undertake to deal with any complaints sympathetically and speedily. If any complaint cannot be resolved to the satisfaction of the customer, we or the customer can refer the problem for conciliation by the Director, Mail Order Traders Association, PO Box 51909, London, SW99 0WZ. 

## Monitoring Communications

As part of our efforts to make further improvements to the service we provide to our customers, telephone calls to and from Next Directory may be recorded or monitored and used for training purposes. To protect the operation of our computer systems we monitor incoming and out going email. 

## Changes to the Privacy Policy

We keep our privacy policy under regular review and we will place any updates in this webpage. This privacy policy was last updated on 5 July 2013. 

## Contact Us

If you have any questions relating to this policy or the use by Next of personal data please write to the Group Data Protection Manager at Head Office or via dataprotection@nextdirect.com, quoting Security and Privacy Enquiry.
